<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Storage on Jineshkumar Patel</title><link>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/tags/storage/</link><description>Recent content in Storage on Jineshkumar Patel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jineshkumar1.github.io/tags/storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>All about Azure Storage</title><link>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/azure-storage-account/azure-storage-account/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/azure-storage-account/azure-storage-account/</guid><description>What is Azure Storage ? Azure Storage is a Microsoft-managed service providing cloud storage that is highly available, secure, durable, scalable, and redundant. Azure Storage includes Azure Blobs (objects), Azure Data Lake Storage Gen2, Azure Files, Azure Queues, and Azure Tables.
Azure Storage Account is what we create on azure to store any kind of Data (Blob Objects, Files, Table, Queue, )
The storage account provides a unique namespace (URL) for your Azure Storage data that is accessible from anywhere in the world over HTTP or HTTPS.</description></item><item><title>Veeam Backup for Azure</title><link>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/veeam-backup-for-azure/veeam-backup-for-azure-deployment-on-azure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/veeam-backup-for-azure/veeam-backup-for-azure-deployment-on-azure/</guid><description>Veeam Backup for AZURE - Deployment on Azure (Native Azure Backup - SaaS) Advantages of Veeam Backup for Azure,
**Your Azure Backup Infrastructure looks like this, ** **Backup Appliance **
The backup appliance is a Linux-based Azure VM where Veeam Backup for Microsoft Azure is installed.
Backup Appliance will run Backup Service, Config. DB, WebUI, Update Service, REST API Service. Backup Repositories A backup repository is a folder in a blob container where Veeam Backup for Microsoft Azure stores backups of Azure VMs Worker Instances</description></item></channel></rss>