<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud on Jineshkumar Patel</title><link>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/tags/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud on Jineshkumar Patel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jineshkumar1.github.io/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Migration from AWS S3 Bucket to Azure Storage</title><link>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/azcopy-migration/azure-azcopy-migration-from-aws-s3-bucket-to-azure-storage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/azcopy-migration/azure-azcopy-migration-from-aws-s3-bucket-to-azure-storage/</guid><description>Azure AZCopy Migration from AWS S3 Bucket to Azure Storage Components we will use,
Install AZCopy Data on AWS S3 bucket which will be the source. Azure Storage Account and Container created there which will be Target. Access and Authorization with Azure and AWS (Using SAS Token and SAK and SKI) Don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you are new to this, I have provided Step by Step Guide on how to use all the above components and AZCopy to migrate Data from AWS S3 to Azure Container.</description></item><item><title>All about Azure Storage</title><link>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/azure-storage-account/azure-storage-account/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/azure-storage-account/azure-storage-account/</guid><description>What is Azure Storage ? Azure Storage is a Microsoft-managed service providing cloud storage that is highly available, secure, durable, scalable, and redundant. Azure Storage includes Azure Blobs (objects), Azure Data Lake Storage Gen2, Azure Files, Azure Queues, and Azure Tables.
Azure Storage Account is what we create on azure to store any kind of Data (Blob Objects, Files, Table, Queue, )
The storage account provides a unique namespace (URL) for your Azure Storage data that is accessible from anywhere in the world over HTTP or HTTPS.</description></item><item><title>Azure function APP with Demo</title><link>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/azure-function-app/create-an-azure-function-app-in-the-azure-portal./</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/azure-function-app/create-an-azure-function-app-in-the-azure-portal./</guid><description>Create an Azure function app in the Azure portal. Azure Functions (FaaS) is simply a platform to upload the application code, run, and manage the application without having to think about setting up any servers.
Serverless compute can be thought of as a &amp;ldquo;function as a service&amp;rdquo; (FaaS), or a microservice that is hosted on a cloud platform. Your business logic runs as functions and you don&amp;rsquo;t have to manually provision or scale infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Deploy DockerHub Images onto Docker Container using Azure Container Instance</title><link>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/deploy-docket-image/deploy-dockerhub-images-onto-docker-container-using-azure-container-instance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/deploy-docket-image/deploy-dockerhub-images-onto-docker-container-using-azure-container-instance/</guid><description>How to Deploy DockerHub Images onto Docker Container using Azure Container Instance Deploy a docker container using container instance from the Azure portal Resource group: Create new &amp;gt; ContainerRG Container name: &amp;ldquo;securedockercontainer&amp;rdquo; Image source: Docker Hub or Other Registry , Image Type: Public Docker Hub Image: glennc/fancypants:latest OS Type: Linux , 1vCPU, 1.5 GBs This image is created by SCOTT HANSELMAN and Glenn C. Who Created .NET WebApp and put it as Public Docker Hub registry here which can be used by Developers to Learn and Test Case purposes.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Voting App using AKS</title><link>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/voting-app-in-aks/deploy-voting-app-using-azure-kubernetes-cluster-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/voting-app-in-aks/deploy-voting-app-using-azure-kubernetes-cluster-service/</guid><description>Deploy &amp;ldquo;Voting App&amp;rdquo; using Azure Kubernetes Cluster Service Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) is a managed Kubernetes service that lets you quickly deploy and manage clusters.
This is a Tutorial on how to deploy a container-based application (Voting-App) using Azure Kubernetes Cluster service.
First, Few very basics about Kubernetes, Kubernetes is a production-ready, portable, open-source platform for managing containerized workloads and services, that facilitates both declarative configuration and automation.
Basically, Kubernetes is a container orchestration tool When you deploy Kubernetes, you get a cluster.</description></item><item><title>How to host your static website using Apache2 on a Linux</title><link>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/host-static-website/host-your-static-website-using-apache2-on-a-linux-machine-deployed-on-azure./</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/host-static-website/host-your-static-website-using-apache2-on-a-linux-machine-deployed-on-azure./</guid><description>How to host your static website using Apache2 on a Linux machine deployed on Azure. In this quick tutorial, We are going to learn Azure Linux VM Configuration, Few Linux VM Commands, and Apache Web Server Install and display our own Webpage on a Public IP address from anywhere.
Deployment Components : Linux VM : Ubuntu Server 20.04 LTS Compute Resources on : **Azure ** Web Server : **Apache2 ** Web Front End : HTML Deployment Steps 1st Step: Deploy Azure Compute Resource : Linux VM (Ubuntu 20.</description></item><item><title>How to PASS AZ-900 Azure Fundamental</title><link>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/pass-az900/how-to-pass-az-900-azure-fundamental/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/pass-az900/how-to-pass-az-900-azure-fundamental/</guid><description>How to PASS AZ-900 Azure Fundamental (Training Materials) AZ-900 Azure Fundamentals All Major Microsoft Azure Associate and Expert Level certifications need a strong Foundation and Azure Fundamentals Certification ( AZ-900 ) is providing just that.
AZ-900 Skills measured The content of this exam was updated on November 9, 2020. Please download the exam skills outline to see what changed.
**Describe cloud concepts (20-25%) ** -&amp;gt;Public/Private/Hybrid Cloud
-&amp;gt;Iaas, PaaS, SaaS,
-&amp;gt;High-Availibility, Scalability, Elasticity, Agility, DR , CapEx vs OpEx,</description></item><item><title>Introduction to ARM Templates</title><link>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/intro-to-arm-template/introduction-to-azure-arm-templates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/intro-to-arm-template/introduction-to-azure-arm-templates/</guid><description>Introduction to ARM Templates (AZURE IaC DevOps)
**ARM (Azure Resource Manager)Templates ** are what really gives us the ability to roll out Azure “Infrastructure as code”.
They are project&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure as Code in a declarative and reusable Template. A way to declare the objects/resources you want, the types, its names, and properties in a JSON ( JavaScript Object Notation ) file format which can be checked into source control and managed like any other code file.</description></item><item><title>SYNC your On-Premise AD with AZURE AD</title><link>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/sync-onprem-ad-to-azuread/how-to-sync-your-on-premise-ad-with-azure-ad-hands-on/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/sync-onprem-ad-to-azuread/how-to-sync-your-on-premise-ad-with-azure-ad-hands-on/</guid><description>How-To SYNC your On-Premise AD with AZURE AD (Hands-On) In this Tutorial Blog, We will integrate a Single Forest On-Premise Active Directory (AD) with our Azure Active Directory(AAD) using
Azure AD Connect &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Azure AD cloud sync&amp;rdquo;
What is Azure AD Connect cloud sync? Azure AD Connect Cloud Sync is a cloud service alternative to Azure AD Connect software. The organization deploys one or more lightweight agents in their on-premises environment to bridge AD and Azure AD.</description></item><item><title>Veeam Backup for Azure</title><link>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/veeam-backup-for-azure/veeam-backup-for-azure-deployment-on-azure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://jineshkumar1.github.io/posts/azure/azure-blogs/veeam-backup-for-azure/veeam-backup-for-azure-deployment-on-azure/</guid><description>Veeam Backup for AZURE - Deployment on Azure (Native Azure Backup - SaaS) Advantages of Veeam Backup for Azure,
**Your Azure Backup Infrastructure looks like this, ** **Backup Appliance **
The backup appliance is a Linux-based Azure VM where Veeam Backup for Microsoft Azure is installed.
Backup Appliance will run Backup Service, Config. DB, WebUI, Update Service, REST API Service. Backup Repositories A backup repository is a folder in a blob container where Veeam Backup for Microsoft Azure stores backups of Azure VMs Worker Instances</description></item></channel></rss>